seagullscientific.com 2017-07-09

# Privacy | BarTender by Seagull Scientific

Last updated 2015.08.20

Seagull Scientific is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use and share information that identifies you or is associated with you ("personal information"). It also explains our use of cookies to store and access information while providing access to our sites.

This Privacy Policy covers all sites in the seagullscientific.com domain, including but not limited to www.seagullscientific.com, support.seagullscientific.com, help.seagullscientific.com, and forums.seagullscientific.com. By using our sites, you are agreeing that we can use cookies in accordance with this Policy.

## Personal Information We Collect

We collect personal information that you voluntarily submit directly to us or our website, including information you provide when you download software, download white papers, complete a form, correspond with us, subscribe to our email lists or respond to surveys or promotions. We also collect personal information indirectly such as information about the pages you look at on the site or the device you use to connect to the site.

The personal information we collect includes:

  * **Contact details:** Such as your name, email address, telephone number and addresses you submit.
  * **Preferences** **:** Choices you make such as email frequency or the language in which to display the website.
  * **How you use and connect to the site:** Such as the pages and links you access, the time you access the site and duration you are on it, the website you come to the site from or go to after leaving the site, selections and choices you make when using the site, the type of device you use to connect to the site, its operating system, browser and applications connected to the site through the device, your Internet service provider or mobile network, and your IP address. Typically, this information is associated with your device and not you as a named individual. However, this information may also be associated with you directly if you have previously submitted personal information.
  * **Your location:** Other than information you choose to provide to us, we do not collect information about your precise location. Your device’s IP address may help us determine an approximate location but this will be no more precise than the city, state or country you are using your device in.
  * **Private messages to us:** Such as email and written correspondence, or the online Contact Us form.
  * **Comments and** **opinions:** Such as comments and opinions when you respond to surveys, competitions and promotions.

## How We Use Your Information

We may use your personal information for these purposes:

  * **Contact details:** To communicate with you directly about our products and services, to provide technical support, to connect you with a product reseller or other service provider, or to answer queries, issues or concerns.
  * **Your preferences:** To manage receipt of emails from us or deliver the site content in your chosen language.
  * **How you use and connect to the site:** To correctly present the site to you on your device; to provide appropriate customized content and information; and to improve the site based on aggregate usage patterns.
  * **Your location:** To ensure the content delivered to you is relevant to the city, state or country in which you are using your device.
  * **Private messages to us:** To help us respond to any query, issue or concern you raise.
  * **Comments and opinions:** To help us respond to any query, issue or concern you raise, and to determine ways we can improve our website, communications, products and services.
  * **All personal information:** To monitor and improve the site and our procedures and processes, and to help us develop new products and services. We may anonymize and aggregate the information we collect so that it does not directly identify you, and then use that anonymized information for purposes that include testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving the site and developing new products and features.

## Information We Share with Third Parties

We may share your personal information with the following parties:

  * **Product resellers:** We may provide your information to a company that resells our products so they can contact you and determine your business need for our products.
  * **Partner companies:** We may share your information with a trusted technology partner or channel partner as part of a joint marketing effort.
  * **Service providers:** Companies that provide a service to us, such as a delivery service that delivers any products you buy to your address, are allowed to use your personal information in accordance with our instructions and are required to keep your information secure.
  * **Purchasers of our business:** Personal information may be disclosed or transferred to buyers or perspective buyers of our business or any of our assets as part of the sale.
  * **Law enforcement, regulators and other parties for legal reasons:** Personal information may be disclosed to third parties to whom we are under a legal obligation to disclose your personal information, or to whom we need to disclose your personal information to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of others, detect and investigate illegal activities and breaches of any agreement we have with you.

We do not sell, rent or otherwise disclose information about identifiable individuals to anyone else except as set out above. We may provide third parties with aggregate statistical information and analytics about users of the site, but we will make sure no one can reasonably be identified from this information before we disclose it.

## Storing and Transferring Your Personal Information

We may store information (including personal information) locally on your device using cookies or other browser and application storage methods. See the “Cookies” section below.

Information you provide through a form on the site may be stored in a marketing database, so we can recognize you and gather usage data when you return to the site; we may use cookies to enable this.

The personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in. Some of these jurisdictions offer differing levels of protection in respect of personal information and may be less protective than the jurisdiction you are typically resident in. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By using our website you are consenting to your personal information being transferred to countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in. If you are outside of the USA, this includes your consent to the transfer and storage of your personal information in the USA.

## Email Marketing and Communications

From time to time we may contact you by email with information about our products and services. If you do not want us to send you email marketing, please contact us. You can also unsubscribe from our marketing emails by clicking on the Unsubscribe link in the emails we send to you.

Channel partners, including product resellers and distributors, and registered product owners cannot opt out of certain types of emails, such as product updates and new releases, end-of-service notices, and other communications related to changes in our products, services or policies.

## Links to Third-Party Sites

The site may contain links to and from third-party websites of technology partners, channel partners, news publications, social media services and others. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those websites.

## Cookies

Cookies are text files, containing small amounts of information, which are downloaded to your browsing device (such as a computer or smartphone) when you visit a website. Cookies can be recognized by the website that downloaded them or by other websites that use the same cookies. This helps websites know if the browsing device has visited them before.

### How We Use Cookies

We do not use cookies for advertising purposes on our site or on third-party sites.

Cookies help us understand how our website is being used, let you navigate between pages efficiently, remember your preferences, and generally improve your browsing experience. Cookies can also help ensure that the content you see on our site is more relevant to you and your interests.

### Types of Cookies We Use

The cookies used on our site are generally in one of the following categories:

  * **Strictly Necessary:** These cookies are essential to make our website work. They enable you to move around the site, use its features.
  * **Analytics:** These cookies collect information about how people use our website, including which pages are visited most often, how people move from one page to another, and if they get error messages from certain pages. These cookies don't gather information that identifies you individually. The information is anonymized and aggregated so we can analyze how our site is performing and how we can improve it.
  * **Functionality:** These cookies remember choices you make and enable our site to provide enhanced features and content to you. For example, these cookies can be remember your language choice or enable you to download software.

### How Long Cookies Stay on a Browsing Device

The length of time a cookie will stay on your browsing device depends on whether it is a “persistent” or “session” cookie. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your browsing device after you have finished browsing until they expire or are deleted.

### First and Third-Party Cookies

“First-party cookies” are cookies that belong to us and that we place on your device. “Third-party cookies” are cookies that another party places on your browsing device when you visit our site.

Third parties set cookies from our website to provide a service to us or a function of the site, but we do not always control how third-party cookies are used. You should check the third party’s website for more information about how they use cookies.

### How to Manage Cookies from This Website

You can usually use the browser through which you are viewing this website to enable, disable or delete cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located in the “Help,” “Tools” or “Edit” settings). Please note that if you set your browser to disable all cookies, you may not be able to access some content and some parts of the website may not work properly.

## Changes to This Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, and so you should review it periodically. When we change this Policy in a material way, we will update the “last updated” date. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Notice to You

If we need to provide you with information about something, whether for legal, marketing or other business-related purposes, we will select what we believe is the best way to get in contact with you. We will usually do this through email. The fact that we may send notices to you will not stop you from being able to opt out of certain types of contact as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Contacting Us

If you have questions, comments or requests regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us.
